Succumb to the darkness.
Nosferatu is a horror, fantasy film directed by Robert Eggers.
A gothic tale of obsession between a haunted young woman and the terrifying
vampire infatuated with her, causing untold horror in its wake.
Ellen Hutter, played by Lily-Rose Depp.
Thomas Hutter, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Count Orlok, played by Bill Skarsgård.
Friedrich Harding, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
Prof. Albin Eberhart von Franz, played by Willem Dafoe.
Anna Harding, played by Emma Corrin.
Nosferatu is a 2024 American Gothic horror film
written and directed by Robert Eggers.
It is a remake of Nosferatu: A Symphony of Horror (1922), which was in
turn inspired by Bram Stoker's novel Dracula (1897).
It stars Bill Skarsgård, Nicholas Hoult, Lily-Rose Depp, Aaron
Taylor-Johnson, Emma Corrin, and Willem Dafoe.
Development began in 2015, when Eggers planned to make it his second film; he described
it as a passion project, but eventually opted to delay its production.
Skarsgård and Depp were cast in lead roles in September 2022.
Filming took place primarily at Barrandov Studios in
Prague between February and May 2023.
Nosferatu had its world premiere in Berlin on December 2, 2024, and was
theatrically released in the United States by Focus Features on December 25.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was a commercial success, grossing $181.8
million worldwide on a $50 million budget, becoming Eggers' highest-grossing film.
At the 97th Academy Awards, the film earned nominations for Best Cinematography, Best
Costume Design, Best Production Design, and Best Makeup and Hairstyling.
The film explores themes of cold, based on novel or
book, vampire, necrophilia, eroticism.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.